Lesson 26  The Teacher's Wish
先生の願い
ある放課後、先生が教室にみんなを集めました。
One day after school, our teacher
asked us to gather in the classroom.
静かな声で、「みんな、
もっと本を読んでほしいの」と言いました。
In a quiet voice, she said,
“I want all of you to read more books.”
「うちの母はいつも、遊ぶ前に宿題を終わらせるように言うの」
と妹が付け加えました。
“My mother always tells me to finish my
homework before I play,” my sister added.
「父さんは週末、家事を手伝ってほし
いって言うんだ」と兄は笑いました。
“My father asks me to help with the
housework on weekends,” my brother laughed.
トムはちょっと照れながら、小さな手紙を渡してくれました。
Tom gave me a small letter with a little shyness.
「誕生日パーティーに来てほしい」と書いてありました。
“I want you to come to my
birthday party,” the letter said.
わたしは、おばあちゃんにも長く元
気でいてほしいと思っています。
I also want my grandmother to
live happily for a long time.
先生は授業の問いについて、深く考えてほしいと言いました。
Our teacher told us to think deeply
about the questions in class.
「学ぶことがどれだけ楽しいか、発見してほしいのよ」と。
“I want you to discover how
fun learning can be,” she said.